<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="inventory_folderlevel" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/oh_039">oh_039</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Miriam Frank Oral Histories on Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender, and Queer Activists in the Labor Movement <num>OH.039</num></titleproper>
        <author>Giana Ricci</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher>
        <p>
          <date>4/1/2015</date>
        </p>
        <address>
          <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
          <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
          <addressline>2nd Floor</addressline>
          <addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline>
          <addressline>special.collections@nyu.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.nyu.edu/about/collections/special-collections-and-archives/special-collections/" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.nyu.edu/about/collections/special-collections-and-archives/special-collections/" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-10-20 03:55:40 -0400</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <repository>
        <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Miriam Frank Oral Histories on Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender, and Queer Activists in the Labor Movement</unittitle>
      <origination label="Creator">
        <persname role="ivr" source="naf">Frank, Miriam</persname>
      </origination>
      <origination label="source">
        <persname role="dnr" source="naf">Frank, Miriam</persname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>OH.039</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.5 Linear Feet</extent>
        <extent altrender="carrier">79 interviews on 144 cassette tapes</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1994/2009" type="inclusive">1994-2009</unitdate>
      <abstract id="aspace_a25b8354b2f2db404b2aed0c9fcc8f42">In preparation for her 2014 book <emph render="italic">Out in the Union: A Labor History of Queer America</emph>, historian Miriam Frank conducted several oral history interviews with lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, and queer labor activists across the United States from 1994-2009. These 79 interviews comprise this oral history collection and cover such topics as family and class identity, the influence of the institutions of the political left and/or the church, and death. Through these interviews, Frank sought to expose individual situations of struggle and to create a detailed history of gay, lesbian, bisexual, transgender, and queer activism in labor unions. Items in this collection have been digitized for researcher use unless otherwise indicated.</abstract>
      <physloc id="aspace_680eaf503ba7958d89591b5f96229518">Materials are located at the Tamiment Library.</physloc>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_20d58b22b7ac60cd995dd37a6409a5c2">Materials are in English</langmaterial>
    </did>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_95eb33aceed31caf5dad5183e8d7ba0c">
      <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
      <p>Materials are open without restrictions.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_cc1dae54a6e21314efb02a9958efbb12">
      <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
      <p>Placed on deposit by Dr. Miriam Frank in 1998; the collection plus additional materials were donated by Frank in 2015. The accession numbers related to these gifts are 1998.022 and 2015.022.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <appraisal id="aspace_22b66c81a9eb92869812e5d08f019766">
      <head>Appraisal</head>
      <p>Duplicate cassettes of some interviews were deaccessioned because they did not contain original content.</p>
    </appraisal>
    <arrangement id="aspace_33d18075e1ddf59f661897e636225219">
      <head>Arrangement</head>
      <p>The order in which these materials were sent to the Tamiment Library has been maintained. The tapes are organized alphabetically by last name.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <bioghist id="aspace_a76b905b2238d276793a432275de0504">
      <head>Biographical Note</head>
      <p>Miriam Frank's exploration into labor-gay alliances began in 1990 with the publication of a handbook titled Pride at Work: Organizing for Lesbian and Gay Rights in Unions, which she co-authored with her wife Desma Holcomb. This project entailed oral history interviews with New York City activists, which sparked Frank's initiative to delve further into the subject.
In 1994 Miriam was awarded New York University's Stephen Charney Vladeck Junior Faculty Fellowship. That year she began conducting interviews in New York City and would travel to six other cities to pursue her research. Her findings eventually culminated in 2014 with the publication of her book Out in the Union: A Labor History of Queer America.</p>
      <p>Frank received her B.A., M.A. and PhD from New York University where she served as an Adjunct Professor and Master Teacher of Humanities 1983-2014. She also taught labor history courses at union extension programs in Detroit and New York City, 1977-2009. She is the author of many other publications including The Life and Times of Rosie the Riveter: the story of three million working women during World War II (1982). In 1994 Miriam was awarded New York University's Stephen Charney Vladeck Junior Faculty Fellowship. That year she began conducting interviews in New York City and would travel to six other cities to pursue her research. Her findings eventually culminated in 2014 with the publication of her book <emph render="italic">Out in the Union: A Labor History of Queer America</emph>. </p>
      <p>Frank received her B.A., M.A. and PhD from New York University where as of 2018 she is a Master Teacher of Humanities. She has also authored many other publications including <emph render="italic">The Life and Times of Rosie the Riveter: the story of three million working women during World War II</emph> (1982). </p>
    </bioghist>
    <prefercite id="aspace_0b63715b050bb11e2c9f8d5ff50cd027">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Identification of item, date; Out in the Union: Gays and Lesbians in the Labor Movement, Miriam Frank Oral History Collection; OH 039; box number; tape number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <processinfo id="aspace_532e58bbc847a663c6f1257a2ade4374">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>At the time of accessioning, a preliminary file list and a collection-level finding aid was created to describe these materials. No physical processing or arrangement was done at this time.</p>
      <p>In 2013-2015 the collection was digitized by the New York University Barbara Goldsmith Preservation and Conservation Department. Through this process, access CDs were created for researcher use, and the original material was placed in archival housing. After the digitization process was finished, a complete finding aid was published in 2015. </p>
    </processinfo>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_53b3742c6a75048fb13a45d63305d009">
      <head>Scope and Contents</head>
      <p>The collection consists of 79 interviews conducted by Miriam Frank in 1994-2009. Possible alternate spellings of interviewee names and/or pseudonyms are noted in the Scope and Contents note of that interview. Summaries of content are also located in the Scope and Contents note for each tape. These summaries are based on Frank's research notes. </p>
      <p>The interviews are both biographical and topical covering such themes as family and class identity, the influence of the political left and/or the church, love, and death. Specific labor topics Frank sought to document were institutional policies and new bargaining issues with regard to lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender and queer workers; the history of gay participation in unions, both hidden and "out"; resistance to LGBTQ workers and activists in some sectors of the labor movement; labor education and AIDS education; the influence of community organizing; and union organizing and collective bargaining in queer community workplaces. </p>
      <p>Through these interviews, Frank sought to expose individual situations of struggle and to create a detailed history of LGBTQ activism in the labor movement. In the course of her research, Frank conducted and recorded over 100 interviews, 79 of which are located at the Tamiment Library. Most of these interviews are quoted and indexed in Frank's book <emph render="italic">Out in the Union: A Labor History of Queer America</emph>.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <phystech id="aspace_de9cb2a9b6b410a8717942f76e457eaa">
      <head>Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures</head>
      <p>Access to audiovisual materials in this collection is available through digitized access copies. Researchers may view an item's original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection's finding aid and can be requested in our reading room. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.</p>
    </phystech>
    <userestrict id="aspace_0a86958699405218b39b688f54bc8f35">
      <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
      <p>Copyright (or related rights to publicity and privacy) for materials in this collection, created by Dr. Miriam Frank, was not transferred to New York University. Permission to use materials must be secured from the copyright holder.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="lcsh">Gay rights -- United States.</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Gay liberation movement -- United States.</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Lesbians -- Employment -- United States</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Gay labor union members |z United States</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Oral history.</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Homosexuality |x Labor unions |z United States</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Discrimination in employment -- United States.</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Homosexuality |x Employment |z United States</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Gays -- Employment -- United States</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Sexual Orientation |z United States</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Labor unions -- United States.</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Women labor union members -- United States.</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Homosexuality -- United States.</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Lesbians -- United States</subject>
      <persname role="dnr" source="naf">Frank, Miriam</persname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c id="aspace_ref21" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Tom Ammiano</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Apr 7, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_059e0d991ed1c5838113596e74aab021" label="master cassette [31142054612455]" type="Box">4</container>
          <container id="aspace_fa1494bb944093c3457709064babb1db" parent="aspace_059e0d991ed1c5838113596e74aab021" type="Cassette">33</container>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_95faa5844c98fc75ac3feea72fc8d208" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_3d3dfbfdb24c53286b08a3bc86ee4cd9">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in San Francisco, CA. Ammiano was a Teacher of Special Education since 1964 and was a member of the American Federation of Teachers Local 61. His interview discusses the topics of support for gay rights in the California Teachers Association, Bay Area Gay Liberation (BAGL), the Gay Teachers Coalition work with Local 61 officials, Board of Education non-discrimination campaign, labor support "No on 6" (Briggs campaign), curriculum changes, gay/lesbian speakers bureau in schools, Gay Teachers march in Gay Freedom and Labor Day parades, working class/gay identity, lost Board of Education election campaign 1980, stand-up performing, winning of Board seat in 1990, labor endorsements, city politics and his election as Supervisor of City of San Francisco in 1994.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref52" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Anonymous SEIU</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Jun 12, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_76043a33f40fc6f5313fc90f155ab0c2" label="master cassette [31142054612471]" type="Box">6</container>
          <container id="aspace_448b85a782d05494402cef3a953e3290" parent="aspace_76043a33f40fc6f5313fc90f155ab0c2" type="Cassette">87-88</container>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_a31d4fb2531dbce4bbac97910a5cbce4" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_d9829a849203af93477e3d92d4fb5352">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Washington D.C. This anonymous interviewee was raised in a Southern town in a racist environment. This interview touches on the topics of class awareness, journalism, VISTA, NOW feminists, her lesbian relationship, SEIU secretary job, coming out to friends, DC lesbian scene, SEIU "Bring a Child to Work Day," not coming out to parents but out in the union, staff union Local 2 OPEIU, domestic partner benefits, SEIU and gay activism, the feature story "Gay Union and Proud" in SEIU national magazine and the positive/negative responses 1993.</p>
          <p>NOTE: Anonymity for reasons of family sensitivity, not union activity. </p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref63" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Connie Ashbrook</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Jul 16, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_1576e040f86efb4ede8899aee2e7b06d" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_76ce0d460999dcc95dc133ce004b3450" label="master cassette [31142054612497]" type="Box">Shared Cassette Box 6</container>
          <container id="aspace_d93941ac1823b197d357c5857833c349" parent="aspace_76ce0d460999dcc95dc133ce004b3450" type="Cassette">109-110</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_8cbfd98bc240f962019dbc0a69b2bf4f">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Portland, OR. Ashbrook was raised in the Midwest and held light industry jobs in the early 1970's. Her interview covers the topics of Ozarks rural commune scene, marriage and divorce, her and lover both school bus drivers, ATU union drive 1977, apprentice truckdriver, harassment, layoff, women's carpenter apprentice program, lesbians/straight women trades network, union meetings UBCJA #1020 (#247), steady work servicing buildings International Union Elevator Constructors #23, elected correspondent to national journal <emph render="underline">Elevator Constructor</emph>, recording secretary labor council delegate, coming out over Prop 9, "No on 13" lunchbox sticker, co-worker reactions, Tradeswomen conference Chicago 1988, Portland Gay Pride march 1993 and 1995 and CLUW and women's involvement in unions.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref30" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Allen Baird</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Apr 11, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_8b94cdf7f83454608c2453798f55533b" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_7ee72f21d7938903fe222652e952fb14" label="master cassette [31142054612489]" type="Box">5</container>
          <container id="aspace_3c6e4b8bd34b31f523b925e96437b82d" parent="aspace_7ee72f21d7938903fe222652e952fb14" type="Cassette">51-52</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_3ab725c156b477c3923ecea13d2dcdba">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>An alternate spelling of this interviewee's first name may be "Allan." This interview took place in San Francisco, CA. At the time of the interview, Baird was a retired president/business representative of newspaper truck drivers Teamster Local 921. A long-time resident of the Castro community, Baird was an advocate of gay/lesbian rights and an activist in Harvey Milk's organization. He was a Local 921 officer in 1962 and was appointed by IBT Western Conference to Local 888 Coors Beer campaign of 1973. His interview discusses the topics of street fights with cartel of Coors distributors, Chinese, Black Panther, Arab and gay community support, Milk's involvement, Coors' biogtry, strength of gay boycott, Teamster hijinks, Coors lie detector policies, Teamster/Farmwork cooperation, IBT internal politics calling off labor boycott, placement of openly gay/lesbian truck drivers, discrimination, legacy of Milk, character in "Harvey Milk" opera of 1995, women's participation in IBT, his activism since retirement, AIDS work in San Francisco, Milk election campaigns, and talk with Jimmy Hoffa about gay labor support in 1974.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref168" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Tom Barbera</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2000/2000" type="inclusive">Apr 14, 2000</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_5319ee3f07e7e68ca82e66c000a24a68" label="master cassette [31142054612455]" type="Box">4</container>
          <container id="aspace_88299bd66c995aba7931f82b332f5fb0" parent="aspace_5319ee3f07e7e68ca82e66c000a24a68" type="Cassette">131-132</container>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_05146b4ac46188b4a9c9e28068b80024" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_5203bd61b98a32b8f244bb30f3a3cc9f">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Boston, MA.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <phystech id="aspace_32fd5c3dd813305f0b68d6831cfca197">
          <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
          <p>This interview is currently being digitized. An access CD is not yet available.</p>
        </phystech>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref44" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Nancy Brown</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">May 1, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_d438fccc2734be0fe71517998791ab57" label="master cassette [31142054612489]" type="Box">5</container>
          <container id="aspace_53dfefa08e7b740d1aec56426320f32f" parent="aspace_d438fccc2734be0fe71517998791ab57" type="Cassette">70-71</container>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_940dfe40440c0f675e5c7f5e2adbe0ad" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_6aeca35fa7d92c6aebc5c726eb4593c3">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Royal Oak (Detroit). Brown was raised in Detroit and Kalamazoo in an Air Force military family. Her interview discusses the topics of her job at the post office in the late 1960's, NALC and sexism, her promotion to supervisor and detachment from harassment, co-worker lesbian relationship, lesbian scene mid-1970's, gay/straight friendships, construction site work culture, comments of racism and homphobia, electrician apprenticeship Local 58 IBEW, sexism at union meetings and at work site, earning respect and finding allies, Detroit Women in Trades, Local 58 union life, union benefits and equity for construction workers' domestic partners.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref64" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Becky Capoferri</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Jul 17, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_0e4db0992af758b18258a75c987f2ffc" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_5f8ff93b53da0a506375333ad8589c31" label="master cassette [31142054612497]" type="Box">Shared Cassette Box 6</container>
          <container id="aspace_0a9877ee18b7e3be5c1e71367bc4f6b6" parent="aspace_5f8ff93b53da0a506375333ad8589c31" type="Cassette">111-112</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_059191039e801c1d2a7ee4147b2ccd41">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Portland, OR. Capoferri was raised in Springfield, OH in a business family. Her interview covers the topics of teenage consciousness of bisexuality, counterculture late 1960's, dropping out of high school, marriage and daughter, mental health work, active OPEU #503 (SEIU) psychiatric aide, gay membership and gay executive council, pay equity strike, non-discrimination in contract, state executive order and origins of Oregon Citizens Alliance anti0gay campaigns 1987, queer identity, OPEU staff 1989, "No on 9" union work, Bob Ralphs' leadership, Oregon Lavendar Labor Action Committee, building queer/Latina coalition HERE #4, defeat of Prop 9 1992, marijuana withdrawl, OPEU strike Spring 1995, NW union women conference queer caucus, queer/labor agenda, and class politics/queer community.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref170" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Donna Cartwright</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2001/2001" type="inclusive">Jul 16, 2001</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_5536ad10d18a9153302fd0644197bd07" label="master cassette [31142054612455]" type="Box">4</container>
          <container id="aspace_28caa374ca21729dbd503782e01ba13f" parent="aspace_5536ad10d18a9153302fd0644197bd07" type="Cassette">133-135</container>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_502e4bb411805f6620bbd314e5c8e902" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref19" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Gerry Casey</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Mar 27, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_67afa3916639ec73188e4531ad88b3dd" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_a34d698ad7e74abbf6b8dbf8ceeaa944" label="master cassette [31142054612455]" type="Box">4</container>
          <container id="aspace_7bca3f800acdb4be4cab2b3a82600c2f" parent="aspace_a34d698ad7e74abbf6b8dbf8ceeaa944" type="Cassette">30</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_69b329f8be56617f7d85004f235741e2">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Boston, MA. Casey grew up in Methuen and was a political activist in the 1960's, a state social worker, and a member of the Local 509 Service Employees union. Her interview discusses the topics of coming out in the early 1970's, non-political friendships, gender and union power, domestic partner benefits in 1994, rank and file gay formations, compulsive union activism, alcoholism, and support from union co-workers during her detox/rehabilitation.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref20" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Shirley Clarke</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Mar 27, 1995</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_2647c8a1442943fd2545e5b5b04695c6" label="master cassette" type="drawer">6.</container>
          <container id="aspace_eb9cc20baf67fe8ba667438c96cb07d9" parent="aspace_2647c8a1442943fd2545e5b5b04695c6" type="Cassette">31-32</container>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_548deab3628f86108beaef79477a7d81" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_84965f6c4e60605abe3fe523f46b530f">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Boston, MA. Clarke spent her childhood in an African American community and experiences sexual abuse by the matrons at her orphanage. She recounts her experiences in foster homes and getting punished for lesbian behavior. She eventually took a housekeeper job at the Statler hilton and joined the Hotel and Restaurant Local 26 union. When she moved back to Boston, she took a state job and joined AFSCME Local 402. Her interview discusses the topics of butch identity, civil rights, her involvement in marches on Washington and Selma, her son's participation in Head Start, community activism, her inter-racial butch/femme marriage of 7 years, Chicago lesbian scene, mid-1970's community mental work, workplace gay culture, union support of gay rights, Washington ACT-UP lock-up, her election as Local 402 Vice President despite gay baiting, gay activists at AFSCME conventions, Local 509 SEIU, Baltimore SEIU Lavendar Caucus conference 1992 and lesbian/black/union family life.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref61" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Shelly Crites</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Jul 14, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_11b2d263f9569eb804ece6beeea943af" label="master cassette [31142054612471]" type="Box">6</container>
          <container id="aspace_3206c34282f8b01c1e84f003a7454042" parent="aspace_11b2d263f9569eb804ece6beeea943af" type="Cassette">106</container>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_8841c665cb7110907e7ae70734fe3077" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_ade96a1c1864efc3e1e0cc6ede65f8b5">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Seattle. Crites was raised in Kansas City and had a drafting job. Her interview discusses the topics of radical politics, SDS Women's caucus, gay liberation, Peace and Freedom Party, International Socialists in the early 1970's, conflict of labor organizing/gay liberation politics, school bus driver of 75 workers, veteran lesbian drivers and their networks, workday and culture of the dispatch office, lesbian identity and worklife, relation of shop to Teamster union, marginal job, safety issues, driving special needs kids, getting hired at xerox/print shop 1973, acquiring commercial print skills, sexism in new press shop, ten years in trade before member of printers union Printing Pressman #39, Graphic Communications union 1982, Seattle reproductive rights activist, open about feminism on job, less open about lesbian identity but printed "No on 13" poster 1978.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref16" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Ginny Cutting</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Mar 24,1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_e241af67e1c55f732afaf06ebe4868d3" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_7de5962cd618dc341523c099e229fc89" label="master cassette [31142054612455]" type="Box">4</container>
          <container id="aspace_83eb62410810f427be7dd3e8b51d684f" parent="aspace_7de5962cd618dc341523c099e229fc89" type="Cassette">25-26</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_8afdd3e6d065668076a31c93d9f0bbba">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Boston, MA. Cutting was raised in a union fmaily in Somerville. Her father was a Teamsters trucker Local 25. She was an organizer for the International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers Local 2222 throughout New England. Her interview covers the topics of empowering women workers, CLUW, conservatism of workers, her enrollment in the University of Massachusetts, coming out through women's softball, lesbian sports culture, her job as a State of Massachusetts AIDS caseworker, her membership in the Service Employees Local 509 union, Yvonne Forrest, gay culture of state workers, her position on the Executive Board of Gay and Lesbian Concerns Committee, GALLAN's Fenway Benefit, her father's death and Boston working class identity.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref3" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Gary Deane</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1994/1994" type="inclusive">Aug 9, 1994</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Manuscript box - Letter - Half" id="aspace_63d29266403211f475ff92d9f5fb7324" label="transcript [31142062672103]" type="Box">3</container>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_bf53697036404925d5bec1604edd61a7" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_23001cfea66d69865f1111bc849f26b5" label="master cassette [31142054612455]" type="Box">4</container>
          <container id="aspace_25dad02493b30bb224ef599abe43f11a" parent="aspace_23001cfea66d69865f1111bc849f26b5" type="Cassette">2-3</container>
        </did>
        <altformavail id="aspace_ed0ffb91ac972fdeabace77ffa571ea3">
          <head>Existence and Location of Copies</head>
          <p>A transcript of this interview is available at the Tamiment Library.</p>
        </altformavail>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_50bb02b4855873589eff92b6a9992003">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in New York City. Gary Deane was raised in Cincinatti, OH with a seminary education. After pursuing a secular college education, Deane came out just before the draft board examination and "1-Y" classification. He was an officer of the Cincinatti NAACP and was an activist in the fair housing movement in the Midwest. He participated in civil rights campaigns to integrate construction unions and mid-1960's cooperative housing projects of the Chicago Joint Board of Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America. Deane was also an openly gay candidate in the 1977 campaign for City Council Brooklyn delegate-at-large and was involved in the founding of the Brooklyn Lambda Independent Democrats. His interview touches on the topics of gay life in Chicago, social life, gay identity in ACWA, conflicts with leadership, career in NYC cooperative housing and activity in NYC Liberal Party.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref50" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Ramon de la Fuente</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Jun 10, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_3690f5e6ffe184d6ff232b1b3bb2ad0e" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_de8969ff7fb83055a5abf4d99b791f3f" label="master cassette [31142054612471]" type="Box">6</container>
          <container id="aspace_5b0f60aa5bfbb50b290b370dd5599b6b" parent="aspace_de8969ff7fb83055a5abf4d99b791f3f" type="Cassette">83-84</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_fe6a4cad2ed1351feb4e1dc80b56b61a">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Washington D.C. De la Fuente was raised in Manila as a Filipino Catholic. His interview discusses the topics of immigration to Philadelphia, speaking Spanish/Tugalog, immigrant culture, secular world 1970's, early gay awareness, language difficulties, ethnic hierarchies, gay bars Philadelphia/Atlantic City, apprenticeship at NASSCO San Diego Navy shipyard 1979, shipyard electrician erotic subculture, homphobia, religious crisis, Fransciscan seminary, fournalism training BNA, active steward Newspaper Guild Local 39, Asian production workers BNA, founder APALA (Asian Pacific AFL-CIO), and BNA domestic partner benefits TNG contract.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref171" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Robert G. De Santis</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1996/1996" type="inclusive">Jun 29, 1996</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_b14789825396cafbef403934b02f88c7" label="master cassette [31142054612455]" type="Box">4</container>
          <container id="aspace_b90b769bc09987cc451a38c38538c2c6" parent="aspace_b14789825396cafbef403934b02f88c7" type="Cassette">136</container>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_0b2f1b448371b004660c2c0db0c2f19d" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_b7d414090e412aa13f6100659f501914">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Oakland, CA.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <phystech id="aspace_e5ae45db17102c91dbb162f0de76fc41">
          <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
          <p>This interview is currently being digitized. An access CD is not yet available.</p>
        </phystech>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref38" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Michael Dias</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Apr 29, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_b43ce0523206afe31b94d39309853366" label="master cassette [31142054612489]" type="Box">5</container>
          <container id="aspace_40e37f60b2c548c0e4e0518c744a7237" parent="aspace_b43ce0523206afe31b94d39309853366" type="Cassette">64</container>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_9fd5285de9a61b32a37b5b8a9b6ea6ce" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_d652df417ce0884904b811b966497be0">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Boston (Detroit). Dias was raised in New Bedford in a Portugese immigrant family. His interview covers the topics of early gay consciousness, navy service as ship's barber, harassment of gay sailors, special education training, non-union state jobs, gay life in Boston in the 1970's, motorcycle leather scene, gay baiting on job, gay theater troupe, SEIU Local 509 1989 steward, his recruitment by Ginny Cutting to the Gay and Lesbian Concern Committee (Lavendar Caucus), coming out on the job, defending gay members and gay identity in union.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref13" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Gary Dotterman</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Mar 23, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_bc715a868d1911bf81295faeae9bf5a5" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_545289e072a9d19290a193bb1f0ca687" label="master cassette [31142054612455]" type="Box">4</container>
          <container id="aspace_8056903bec64761069baa53685c866b9" parent="aspace_545289e072a9d19290a193bb1f0ca687" type="Cassette">19-20</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_bcf0bc6942ac39c9f39c7a955f07753d">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Boston, MA. Dotterman was raised in Tulsa in the late 1940's in a union family. His interview covers the topics of work in local Democratic clubs, volunteering in the 1960 JFK campaign, the African American community in Tulsa, CORE, Freedom Summer, Vietnam service, criticism of US policy, military investigation, suppression of gay urges, contact with Soviet officials, Arthur Goldberg, 1966 anti-war demonstrations in Tulsa, Bobby Kennedy campaigns, National Welfare Rights Organization, march on Wisconsin legislature, NYC Jews for Urban Justice, contact with gay rap groups, early 1970's Dump Nixon with Allard Loewenstein, McGovern campaign, coming out in Boston, 1970's bar scene as bouncer at The Other Side, lobbying for gay rights, Sylvia Sidney, class consciousness, working as an aide to Councilman David Skondras, Coors boycott mid-1980's, housing advocacy HERE Local 26, and 1986 Communist Party membership.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref65" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Madelyn Elder </unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Jul 17, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_8d5d86578fed5dc96c558d3929f13f88" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_9cb2837413b9cf35d4cacf6db004c672" label="master cassette [31142054612497]" type="Box">Shared Cassette Box 6</container>
          <container id="aspace_c5d8bb19027fa20a94a3f27a6029e08b" parent="aspace_9cb2837413b9cf35d4cacf6db004c672" type="Cassette">113</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_8f4eaa48fe2502863ebcdf28a246ca8a">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Portland, OR. Elder was raised in smalltown Central Illinois in a pro-labor professional family. Her interview discusses the topics of high school feminism, gay liberation early 1970's, union job CWA Ann Arbor, search for left politics in Detroit mid-1970's, Seattle Radical Women 1977-1986, chief steward organizing safety wildcat CWA #9102 (later 7800) 1980, Seattle Initiative 13 and controversy over coalition work in CWA local union and King County Labor Council: non-traditional women workers dyke baited, anti-gay members, CWA #9102 discriminated gay comrade Jonathon Foe Freedom Socialist telephone intaller shop steward, Radical Women work, CWA delegate Labor Council, move to Portland for Radical Women 1986, shop steward CWA #7901, No on 9 plant gate organizing with gay machinist Joe Keir, No on 13 grassroots campaign, gay neutrality Prop 8 public employees rights, and community coalition Progressive Queers 1994-1995.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref173" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Shelley Ettinger</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1998/1998" type="inclusive">Sep 11, 1998</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_d78bff2bfacface395139168f9756fc6" label="master cassette [31142054612455]" type="Box">4</container>
          <container id="aspace_96fc8622b0da25fc0a500fbc414c063a" parent="aspace_d78bff2bfacface395139168f9756fc6" type="Cassette">137-138</container>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_1592dfd4893871adda10c4ddfef4a752" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_8cc1ba6c405e5e1378517e942bbd6601">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in New York City.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref17" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Tess Ewing</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Mar 25, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_644572414a4c36fb53d18e1a1f051c35" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_642735d3b7fd4e0ae0a229382c39dc7c" label="master cassette [31142054612455]" type="Box">4</container>
          <container id="aspace_c92ce73a88051572c34303e968409ad6" parent="aspace_642735d3b7fd4e0ae0a229382c39dc7c" type="Cassette">27-28</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_2f9073f37edb324908b3528519834488">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Boston, MA. Ewing had a middle class upbringing in Swampscott, MA. She came out in 1970 in the women's movement Bread &amp; Roses. Her interview covers the topics of tenant activism, skilled labor, a union drive led by her lover at the Pre-Term Abortion Clinic, school bus drivers organizing with Teamsters 829 in 1976, Workers World and Teamsters/Amalgamated Transit jurisdictional dispute leading to chartering Steelworkers 8751, sexism, lesbian presence in bus yard, lesbian work-place culture, GALLAN, Central America activism, and lesbian caucus Women's Institute for Leadership Development (WILD) 1988.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref7" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Gerry Faier</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Feb 13, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_425dc577710c1dbb160d7c46ce3721a0" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_b03fe73e0fcb9493dd30960385c1f1e8" label="master cassette [31142054612455]" type="Box">4</container>
          <container id="aspace_be798d00a4fd3984395145412450f10e" parent="aspace_b03fe73e0fcb9493dd30960385c1f1e8" type="Cassette">6-7</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_8fe8621085e27f27103aa260bdb629aa">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in New York City. Gerry Faier was born in 1908 to Russian Orthodox Jewish immigants in Boro Park. Faier educated himself at the New York Public Library and eventually became the leader of the Boro Park Unemployment Council and a member of the Communist Party. In his attempts for employment at the Brooklyn Navy Yard, Faier was blackballed for being a communist. His interview discusses the topics of rebellion against family, being a welfare recipient, activity with a clandestine social workers union, his life and love with an older Catholic man, coming out in Woodstock artist bar, his friendship with artists such as Franz Kline and writers such as James Baldwin, comfort with underground gay life, the bars in the Village, and his involvement as a founding member of Senior Action in a Gay Environment (SAGE).</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref165" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>James N. Green</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1997/1997" type="inclusive">Jan 10, 1997</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_b8735058aff5a921a01235b4124de0f5" label="master cassette [31142054612455]" type="Box">4</container>
          <container id="aspace_a7bbbad5cbc77cbd50334d01e5ebb92d" parent="aspace_b8735058aff5a921a01235b4124de0f5" type="Cassette">126-127</container>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_5d2bc58194d3d572dd08673ec9676880" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_d261d0ba1677b1a7afc3569c79c334af">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in New York City.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref9" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Jackie Harris</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Mar 1, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_279be4ea7c0d6acdb47c3d1f6201f1c3" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_9cb83cb753f3e8edce7219af95d626f6" label="master cassette [31142054612455]" type="Box">4</container>
          <container id="aspace_7d9b9646ae8eb93bec3503610ef7bb3c" parent="aspace_9cb83cb753f3e8edce7219af95d626f6" type="Cassette">11-12</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_c5dbaccba1931a4df0f7a0d45b32ed0b">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in New York City. Jackie Harris grew up in Brooklyn, NY as a tomboy with a heritage of union respect in her African American family. She was involved in the civil rights and black power movements in the 1960's as well as the March on Washington of 1963. Her first union membership came as a social caseworker in Local 371, DC 37 ASFSCME. Her interview covers the topics of racial oppresion, interracial relationships, social life with gay house parties, black people in the gay world, CORE activity, picketing Woolworths, Communist Party circles, her visit to Cuba in the early 1960's, FBI harrassment, activity in strike of 1967, division of work and social life with gay co-workers, promotions at job, her election as local delegate, and fiscal malfeasance in union hierarchy.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref23" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Karin Hart</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Apr 7, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_b7f39e952e4458bb6c47a14ead5b3f77" label="master cassette [31142054612455]" type="Box">4</container>
          <container id="aspace_f1c3b863cb2d00612275c169c07f4e64" parent="aspace_b7f39e952e4458bb6c47a14ead5b3f77" type="Cassette">36-37</container>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_5bf526323e850f9f624efd3bc8fcdbca" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_6471a13192a8214916c1ec66d98bf340">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Oakland, CA. Hart spent her childhood in Sunnyvale. Her mother was a teacher union activist and subscribed to the AFL-CIO newsletter. Hart was a student activist in the 1970's and became a phone company installer in 1978. Her interview covers the topics of strike strategies, high school lesbian consciousness, Briggs Initiative, climbing poles and support in nontraditional work, Central America and the CIA, Communications Workers union membership and stewardship, lesbian identity on the job and in Bay Area labor councils, social affairs, rural Califronia, gay/lesbian issues in unions, domestic partner benefits, CWA convention constitutional amendment 1984, later gay/lesbian caucus, Minority Caucus coalition, Cal Noyce's leadership, labor studies Antioch College, and the first Executive Vice President Local 9415. </p>
          <p>NOTE: This material continues in Karin Hart/Naomi Groeschel interview. </p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref24" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Karin Hart/Naomi Groeschel</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Apr 7, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_17e81022727feb5f0cd27208e30ba7d0" label="master cassette [31142054612489]" type="Box">5</container>
          <container id="aspace_3b91f93cd7eaa6a24f6737edea239d77" parent="aspace_17e81022727feb5f0cd27208e30ba7d0" type="Cassette">38</container>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_6a4fcdef2bd050c06b6dddd9ad0e0b5e" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_6d2a4c102d24a8a3ee3b02888c60e1ea">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Oakland, CA. Groeschel's mother was an organizer with the NYC Furriers in the 1930's. Naomi came out as a teenager and was active in the 1970 formation of the Union Women's Alliance to Gain Equality (Union WAGE). She was a local union steward and later a chief union steward of CWA #9415. Her ten year relationship with Karin Hart began with local union meeting and Christmas party. This interview covers the topics of lesbian identity in WAGE, repair and service jobs, Hart's election to Executive Board and then first Vice President of Local 9415, other lesbian CWA activist couples, and Naomi's Union WAGE work with Jean Maddox, Ann Draper, and Joyce Maupin.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref37" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Ann Heler</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Apr 28, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_95276a91818f40588693f7ec7b193e8b" label="master cassette [31142054612489]" type="Box">5</container>
          <container id="aspace_593396a8280f97c62f0deaa21b7482c3" parent="aspace_95276a91818f40588693f7ec7b193e8b" type="Cassette">63</container>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_f3e95ecb6be1eab26f0f80147803a91d" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_7839c12747be9f1de1e722e0ea794445">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Detroit. Heler was a Wayne County teacher who received support from the leadership of Michigan Federation for Teachers for Gay/Lesbian Task Force. Her interview discusses the topics of the danger of women in trades coming out on the job in Michigan, homosexuality and teaching, her teaching of sexuality issues to people who were severely learning disabled, lesbian identity at workplace, Frank Colosanti gay high school counselor coming out in 1989, teachers' fears with gay/lesbian students, gay issues in union contract, closeted students, homophobic parents, state guidelines on sexuality education, union grass roots politics, being a single divorced working mother, coming out at age 40, lesbian/gay community organizing Ferndale 1990's, Michigan Gay Games delegation 1994, and right wing forces in local school politics.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref47" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Mary Kay Henry</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Jun 8, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_1fed5fce952cb2814592206d8a0acff7" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_a7a10f25f2020614478d4eb53a951705" label="master cassette [31142054612471]" type="Box">6</container>
          <container id="aspace_e4ba4bfb9184aafa8e12b1f8f2d3b0e2" parent="aspace_a7a10f25f2020614478d4eb53a951705" type="Cassette">76-77</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_c2f4f927c14fd37b26e6e9d098ed665d">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Washington D.C. Henry was raised in Arizona and the Detroit area. In high school she was an organizer for anti-hunger, college reproductive rights, and labor studies. She came out in the late 1970's and was greatly influenced by the UAW Women's Department and CLUW. Her interview covers the topics of hospital work, union training California SEIU, Elinor Glenn mentoring SEIU women, negotiations and lobbying Minnesota, emerging lesbian identity, coming out publicly and union policy, gay pride labor contingents San Francisco, Los Angeles, Minneapolis, balance of career/relationship, DC gay/labor organizing, health care reform and ENDA issues, living two lives, friends with AIDS in San Francisco mid-1980's, finding integrations with Local 250 AIDS committee, union as community center, Colorado/Oregon initiatives ealy 1990's, lesbian/gay labor politics, SEIU Lavendar Caucus, SEIU Health Care Division Director, restructuring health care and coalition work, labor movement heritage and social issue agenda, J. Sweeney and SEIU gay agenda and Stonewall Pride at Work conference 1994.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref10" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Ruth Jacobson</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Mar 6, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_8ea6e6a6770bb950d3cdf50f9f79941a" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_a7dd76ff238d4e1fe1f3da9e8a3aed4b" label="master cassette [31142054612455]" type="Box">4</container>
          <container id="aspace_ee656d6ce11ffa0230b8da2d760689b9" parent="aspace_a7dd76ff238d4e1fe1f3da9e8a3aed4b" type="Cassette">13-14</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_f1f85b188cf9e2cda0834d721b3e6961">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>An alternate spelling for the last name of this interviewee may be "Jacobsen." This interview took place in Southampton, NY. Ruth Jacobson grew up in Holland and was a Jewish "hidden child" in World War II. She immigrated to NYC and trained as a typist, receiving her first job with the Girl Scouts. She came out in the early 1950's through the YWCA. Her interview covers the topics of 1950's social life in village bars and house parties, going to work parties with gay men, 1960's advertising art, sex discrimination, EEOC complaint, feeling normal about living a double life, long term marriages, anti-war work, breaking into the projectionist trade, Local 306 IATSE NYC, first female "boothman," gender differences and skilled work, mentoring influence of Steve D'Anzillo Local 306 president, her partner Jean LaBerge, acceptance of their relationship in union culture, and helping women enter the union.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref176" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Ann Jochems</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation">Feb 24, 1999</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_4c6fae73fcde1388fe21c064c3f2b8b4" label="access cd [31142062758894]" type="Box">2</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_934e211d0ce5084bcce6febd1b96a821" label="master cassette [31142054612455]" type="Box">4</container>
          <container id="aspace_797843f938399472dbaf865444b4bd01" parent="aspace_934e211d0ce5084bcce6febd1b96a821" type="Cassette">140</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_bbd724b15626cd9b15bdf1f6d001cb65">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in New York City.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref29" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Walter Johnson</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Apr 11, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_095d7297810d7628cc396cbd9550defd" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_55b966ceeaacd756f24d7acf4736d5c0" label="master cassette [31142054612489]" type="Box">5</container>
          <container id="aspace_3148cd6df81432eaa99b1832294d7cb0" parent="aspace_55b966ceeaacd756f24d7acf4736d5c0" type="Cassette">50</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_9a833e8ab20a07f4402b49822eebddb7">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in San Francisco, CA. Johnson was a long-time advocate for civil and lesbian/gay rights. He was Secretary-Treasurer of the San Francisco Labor Council and a member and then the president of Local 1100 Department Store Employees (Retail Clerks) from 1957-1985. His interview discusses the topics of history breaking color bar, advancing gay workers in retail, gay men active in union early 1960's, promotion of gay arbitration, defense of cross-dressing/transsexual worker in the 1970's, educating members, domestic partner benefits, police raids, lesbian store workers, speech at rally for Briggs campaign 1978 and working with the gay community.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref57" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Marcy Johnson</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Jul 13, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_c2382ce32ec5ef3bf46465c2172afd20" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_e6fb6442ebaadb304955ed1eaffe29e6" label="master cassette [31142054612471]" type="Box">6</container>
          <container id="aspace_23cef2879ad5bc6eeb588c21e3f607fa" parent="aspace_e6fb6442ebaadb304955ed1eaffe29e6" type="Cassette">100</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_d13735fd259ebd8d3f957e810a89aaa4">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>An alternate spelling for the last name of this interviewee may be "Johnsen." This interview took place in Seattle. Johnson was raised in Seattle in a railroad Teamster family. Her interview covers the topics of the Seattle bar scene in the 1960's, sexual abuse by her father, being selectively out at work, union member AFSCME, LPN supervisor, RN diploma studies, nurse union activist SEIU 1199 Northwest, district rank/file vice president, initiatives 608/610 Hands Off Washington discussion at Executive Board, Diversity Panel and coming out to 1199 delegate assembly 1993, homophobia, size discrimination, SEIU Lavendar Caucus, Stonewall 25 Pride at Work, Hands Off organizing and Seattle Gay Pride 1995 labor contingent.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref182" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>James Justen</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1996/1996" type="inclusive">Jun 28, 1996</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_0048859b2e1a090f513f70d7217daff2" label="master cassette [31142054612455]" type="Box">4</container>
          <container id="aspace_21de222a846aeaea91b9866524364b6d" parent="aspace_0048859b2e1a090f513f70d7217daff2" type="Cassette">144</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_f28452e3f4e621a6627abf71a86b82e5">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Kenosha, Wisconsin.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref178" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Gary Kapanowski</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2001/2001" type="inclusive">Feb 12, 2001</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_827f1d75a588c92c925ba7958b85299e" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_49170abda5226f3ca6732efa4cf6ff4f" label="master cassette [31142054612455]" type="Box">4</container>
          <container id="aspace_66ae871f3f74d4d8ab9ec3972cfc5663" parent="aspace_49170abda5226f3ca6732efa4cf6ff4f" type="Cassette">141-143</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_1a6d50ec24815a5662743933021b6dbd">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Philadelphia, PA.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <phystech id="aspace_fce0ad7064ba9bf4f177b673ad8fa173">
          <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
          <p>This interview is currently being digitized. An access CD is not yet available.</p>
        </phystech>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref58" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Cathy Kaufman</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Jul 13, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_26d80c888cf2ef1af042f467415e23e0" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_e872453090e6b63fec7c9b182aa822e1" label="master cassette [31142054612471]" type="Box">6</container>
          <container id="aspace_942b25263826290731c61e2ffe02b3c5" parent="aspace_e872453090e6b63fec7c9b182aa822e1" type="Cassette">101</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_faf3ea96515e1f0c9be3ef579ee3556c">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Tacoma (Seattle). Kaufman was raised in Cleveland, OH in a union family involved with IBEW, UAW, APWU, AFT. Her interview covers the topics of class hardships, attending Catholic high school in the mid-1970's, Ohio Citizen Action corporate tax campaign, radical political scene, Toledo feminist community, seniors and low-key lesbian identity, NOW lesbian committee, other anti-homphobia projects 1980's, nursing home organizing SEIU #767, staff 1199 Northwest, health care politics, initiatives 608/610 OutFront Labor Coalition, gay/lesbian community and class consciousness, labor movement and gay identity, and Pride at Work.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref39" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Lisa Kelly</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Apr 29, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_f9a9fa85f1938021208b2f9fa15a30f7" label="master cassette [31142054612489]" type="Box">5</container>
          <container id="aspace_e44d4f637e68a2a918247bbcaadb29b9" parent="aspace_f9a9fa85f1938021208b2f9fa15a30f7" type="Cassette">65</container>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_9bd2895826c91bbce195d0287af77924" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_e53388e4ea6cdfda62fc2e06cae78db5">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Toronto (Detroit). Kelly was not herself a lesbian but was an advocate for lesbian and gay caucus and a staff lawyer for the Canadian Auto Workers. Her interview discusses the topics of same sex benefits, the needs of gay/lesbian members in union apparatus, how lesbian voices emerged at annual CAW women's conference 1993, formation of caucus, top officers encouraging Gay/Lesbian caucus at Quebec CAW convention 1994, role of CAW Women's Department, involving gay men, cooperation of Canadian Public Workers, claims in Big Three Auto, developing policy grievances on gay discrimination, Big Three same sex spousal benefits negotiations, Canadian pension law, visibility problems, CAW culture, Canadian Labor Congress support of gay rights, her feminist childhood, law background and her commitment to gay family and friends and social justice.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref175" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>James Justen</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1996/1996" type="inclusive">Jun 28, 1996</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_25a2a8d64d5175666711d1eafb5cffdc" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_3e8e443c7f6b111dff9f2b14339e8a54" label="master cassette [31142054612455]" type="Box">4</container>
          <container id="aspace_837e6a7a12e794893f747398c6484c82" parent="aspace_3e8e443c7f6b111dff9f2b14339e8a54" type="Cassette">139</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_05ed6bfb4f21c9bb5883534b1839b09b">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Kenosha, Wisconsin.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <phystech id="aspace_4635bfda191a652cb3851a1854db7230">
          <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
          <p>This interview is currently being digitized. An access CD is not yet available.</p>
        </phystech>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref1" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Darin Kinzer</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Jun 14, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_57eb6f472f43280bcd2b9971922a82d5" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_1b63b59afdc336bb9ebd3fb0632093bd" label="master cassette [31142054612471]" type="Box">6</container>
          <container id="aspace_8a9c72824f97c7480fa9399bc39f6831" parent="aspace_1b63b59afdc336bb9ebd3fb0632093bd" type="Cassette">93-94</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_f987c3433328fd88d5a96cdd9b99140b">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Washington D.C. Kinzer was raised in St. Paul, Minnesota. His father was in unions and had a liberal Farmer-Labor German Catholic background. His interview discusses the topics of Frontlash, early gay awareness, sensitivity to prejudice against Southeast Asian immigrants, Minneapolis/St. Paul gay newspapers, Frontlash Mondale campaign 1984, contacts with the Social Democrats USA especially Tom Kahn Assistant to AFL-CIO presidents (Meany and Kirkland) since 1972, Tom's mentoring/gay life, meeting Bayard Rustin, Sandy Feldman, staff SDUSA 1987, SDUSA structure, politics and ideology, Darin's intimate support while Tom was dying of AIDS, staff Free Trade Union Institute, homophobic harassment, hate crime lawsuit, front page story Washington <emph render="underline">Blade</emph>, widespread exposure in AFL-CIo 1991, Lambda Labor DC contingent Gay Pride parade, Stonewall 25 NYC 1994, and producing Tom's memorial at AFL-CIO 1992.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref2" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Connie Kopelov</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1994/1994" type="inclusive">Jul 14, 1994</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_3c33927f21424438f1fd9f30ca7e8bed" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container altrender="Manuscript box - Letter - Half" id="aspace_2d21f42c68777af018861e3194e05394" label="transcript [31142062672103]" type="Box">3</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_c85395d06c4ce5a502549ec43a384753" label="master cassette [31142054612455]" type="Box">4</container>
          <container id="aspace_1b690c5f7ddd9b252a9adde18b868c8e" parent="aspace_c85395d06c4ce5a502549ec43a384753" type="Cassette">1</container>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="aspace_610da8144bcc55fe69af05035c2c3292">
          <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
          <p>Connie Kopelov and her partner Phyllis Siegel were the first couple in New York City to be pronounced married on the first day that the Marriage Equality law took effect in 2011. Connie Kopelov's interview was the first of over 100 conducted by Miriam Frank as the groundwork for <emph render="italic">Out in the Union: A Labor History of Queer America</emph>.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <altformavail id="aspace_23ac5cb8f8bb36383e4ab1de0740e26d">
          <head>Existence and Location of Copies</head>
          <p>A transcript of this interview is available at the Tamiment Library.</p>
        </altformavail>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_da3d8bfa4e8f7342ef74af5a4d3f97fc">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in New York City. Kopelov was raised in Kokomo, Indiana and her college education and early career was dedicated to civil liberties. She participated in the labor education in the late 1950's through 1970's of the staff of the Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America and late District 1199. Kopelov was also an early organizer and staff member of the Coalition of Labor Union Women. Her interview touches on the topics of coming out, relationships, lesbian and social life in New York City in the early 1960's, necessity of self-censorship, union women, sexism, and sources of support and discrimination in the CLUW and ACWA.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref60" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Virginia LaGasa</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Jul 14, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_b7e7018f8f4fbe7111a7dbd8231edf7d" label="master cassette [31142054612471]" type="Box">6</container>
          <container id="aspace_4f6ce9d02a82d2a89a27823f7786704e" parent="aspace_b7e7018f8f4fbe7111a7dbd8231edf7d" type="Cassette">104-105</container>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_d79fef13f26723102db25f62300e130d" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_958b738750187da417e1a464d1cd52d6">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Tacoma (Seattle). LaGasa was raised in Southern California by her grandmother who was an anti-union bakery owner. Her interview discusses the topics of being a teenage lesbian, Hollywood bar scenes, heroin use and juvenile arrests, police harassment, alcohol and prescription drugs 1950's, street life, proprietor massage parlors, pregnancy and co-parenting, adoption of ex-lover's baby, factory jobs, motherhood in the mid-1960's, forced resignation LA County job, sobriety crisis early 1970's, finding lesbian support, Orange County NOW 1973, gay hotline network, awards for college work on chemical dependency, gay rights ASLU, anti-Briggs campaign late 1970's, group home counselor, union job Pierce County AFSCMe #53 state facility 1987, statewide AFSCME taskforce and other Tacoma gay/lesbian union activists 1990's.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref11" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Sandra Lara</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Mar 21, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_bdff1a6908abc46d7adb41f27dc86a52" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_6f8341a0574f7a14c1f67ba8f6963e1c" label="master cassette [31142054612455]" type="Box">4</container>
          <container id="aspace_a518285f740401eaa0f042eca8c6d3da" parent="aspace_6f8341a0574f7a14c1f67ba8f6963e1c" type="Cassette">15-16</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_1cc99ad133133b1580ddcf3e3d009305">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in New York City. Lara grew up in a Puerto Rican/Italian family in a Jersey shore community. Her interview covers the topics of women's liberation, psychotherapy, butch identity, drugs and involvement in a spiritual cult, gender realtions on job, Ashram identity, being a member of CWA Local 1101, Marxist study group late 1970's, sexual harassment, sexist bosses, her election as a shop steward, 1980's writing for <emph render="underline">The Generator</emph> about political issues, AIDS training, strike activism in 1990 and gay identity at union conferences.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref25" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Audrey Lehmann</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Apr 8, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_787710c125238797af656ab6b798a8b1" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_b59537184ab2fd3f18410a9cce9d1790" label="master cassette [31142054612489]" type="Box">5</container>
          <container id="aspace_1e4229794643afc4e274925210abc21b" parent="aspace_b59537184ab2fd3f18410a9cce9d1790" type="Cassette">39</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_342e88114d50d1c505be6cc510e88d55">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in San Francisco, CA. At this time, Lehmann was described as a "young punk dyke" in her mid-20s. Her interview covers the topics of labor and queer consciousness, union family, factory work in union shop, safeway supermarket strike, conflicts with her brother about crossing the picket line, politics, sexuality and solidarity.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref14" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Janice Loux</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Mar 23, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_31f17b3b9052bbc9f38fe3b055500556" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_a93c9098f5f2138d00d85700af9cfe32" label="master cassette [31142054612455]" type="Box">4</container>
          <container id="aspace_df5b06fd2701083df49261f06b246912" parent="aspace_a93c9098f5f2138d00d85700af9cfe32" type="Cassette">21-22</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_9c246f617377d6201cbdb93be9d6d212">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Boston, MA. Loux was raised in South Boston in a union family. Her mother was an activist in Local 26 Hotel and Restaurant Employees. Her interview covers the topics of her mother's sex discrimination suit of 1965, strike threats, progressive reforms, coming out in 1987-1989, personal support from Gay and Lesbian Labor Activists Network of Boston (GALLAN), work with members with AIDS, negotiating details of domestic partner and extended family benefits in union trusts, reform of Taft Hartley housing trust, grievance, coalition with ACT UP on AIDS discrimination, race and class issues in AIDS service, Local 26 record on gay issues, integration of union and personal life, and advice to other HERE activists.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref5" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Judy Mage</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1994/1994" type="inclusive">Aug 16, 1994</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Manuscript box - Letter - Half" id="aspace_6fff0a35dae2df08ea5dbddebddf3a70" label="transcript [31142062672103]" type="Box">3</container>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_47c00fad0c9786a028f574d2fd915a24" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_46c0aa2058a9cfbe70a9410dfb1ba800" label="master cassette [31142054612455]" type="Box">4</container>
          <container id="aspace_3b03b5992e151202234b64de96c6644e" parent="aspace_46c0aa2058a9cfbe70a9410dfb1ba800" type="Cassette">4-5</container>
        </did>
        <altformavail id="aspace_4b8007c2dbbd00e05e152d6352034eb8">
          <head>Existence and Location of Copies</head>
          <p>A transcript of this interview is available at the Tamiment Library.</p>
        </altformavail>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_df3f3d8b25781c2017703fd610ed6a4b">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in New York City (New Platz). Judy Mage was raised in the Bronx, NY. In the early 1960's she held a job as a caseworker at the NYC Welfare Department, was an organizer of the Social Services Employees Association (SSE) and was a member of the Socialist Workers Party. Her interview touches on the topics of the conflict between AFSCME Local 371 and SSE, intergration of client advocacy, welfare rights, lesbianism, bisexuality, coming out into Village gay bars, Socialist Workers Party and faction battles, labor activism, union social life, her relationship with an union activist co-worker, SSE strike of 1964, her romance in prison with a Local 371 activist and her disillusionment with the welfare reform movement.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref27" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Leslie Manning</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Apr 10, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_d976fb19195261ff96420b368c753e6b" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_49ae9d6ac51403194f6250d08351cad2" label="master cassette [31142054612489]" type="Box">5</container>
          <container id="aspace_f247e25d50d0837ca47bd825c91be52f" parent="aspace_49ae9d6ac51403194f6250d08351cad2" type="Cassette">44-45</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_282c607e94b42119bbf916e9979e5524">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in San Francisco, CA. Manning was raised in Rhode Island in an Irish-American carpenter union family. Her interview discusses the topics of NYC theater production gigs mid-1970's, NYC IATSE stage managers local, her move to San Francisco in 1979, activism gay/labor political scene, Labor Neighbor electoral education/action program 1994, Gay Freedom Parades, freelance mediation and fundraising work, early 1980's, producing of Democratic Convention Gay/Lesbian rally 1984, union labor at Women's Music Festivals, memories of gay activists committed to labor such as George Mendenhall, Gary Parker, Bill Kraus, Cleve Jones, Teamsters 921 newspaper driver job late 1980's, Coors boycott, AIDS and tricking among truckers, gay subculture, Teamster's women conference, open about her gay marriage in union, shop steward, Recording Secretary Labor Council delegate, 1994 SF newspaper strike, building gay/lesbian presence in newspaper unions, and community wide support for the strike.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref167" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Scott Melvin</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2001/2001" type="inclusive">Feb 27, 2001</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_397f6578570bef53e9cb49d28cee747d" label="access cd [31142062758894]" type="Box">2</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_d6e607ceb5a268a3407935503c3ef906" label="master cassette [31142054612455]" type="Box">4</container>
          <container id="aspace_f01582266d3fc0a23665fd762a2a9773" parent="aspace_d6e607ceb5a268a3407935503c3ef906" type="Cassette">128-130</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref66" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>James Mitchell</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Aug 11, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_04bb79a8effb89dff7b182fbfff4aa4b" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_1f54e1136d1d6da4113904d4bd0d38f2" label="master cassette [31142054612497]" type="Box">Shared Cassette Box 6</container>
          <container id="aspace_12005be2e6ab7ac94243c45a3bf32b0c" parent="aspace_1f54e1136d1d6da4113904d4bd0d38f2" type="Cassette">115-117</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_90716829d60e724de7246bb731a5f71d">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in New Rochelle, NY. </p>
          <p>Tape #115: Mitchell was raised in Bronxville and his father was a salesman. This tape includes the topics of his parents' divorce, wartime survival 1930's, college fraternity scene and gay affairs, crisis over Episcopal vocation 1950's, homophobia and teachers, McCarthy, Greenwich Village, gay scene 1950's, GLF and AFT radicals, GAA 1960's, Fire Island cruising, NYC sex busts, Columbia Teachers, Social Studies certification 1960, Freeport JHS and racism and Jewish friends.</p>
          <p>Tape #116: New Rochelle community values, tenure 1966, gay identity, lover Walter Weeks MD, gay VD practice and holding drugs, army service, breakup and suicide 1967, student protests civil rights/Vietnam, teaching black studies, prominent academics in-service course late 1960's, Role of Supt of Schools, false AIDS diagnosis, district-wide AIDS policy 1986, being outed by colleague, NEA/AFT union work, AFT elected 1967, VP membership 1972, President 1981.</p>
          <p>Tape #117: union responsibilies, conflicts with management, high school burned down from arson 1968, differences with SWP union president strike 1969, NEA conflicts, teacher/civil service merger AFT 1979, gay/lesbian AFT caucus activits, homphobia and sex harassment grievance 1994-1995, AIDS information workshops mid-1980's, school board approved gay/lesbian student group and teacher workshop and troubled gay/lesbian teenagers. </p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref15" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Susan Moir</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Mar 23, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_865e4579af065ac3cb6e56e449873abc" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_404da668d9a3ca945bcbd3350988deec" label="master cassette [31142054612455]" type="Box">4</container>
          <container id="aspace_febcbd748e638c5e2d00deb1e933a472" parent="aspace_404da668d9a3ca945bcbd3350988deec" type="Cassette">23-24</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_79916acef10999f195ea9394a14bacff">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Boston, MA. Moir grew up in a working class anti-union family in "Cork City," an Irish-American community. Her interview covers the topics of childhood lesbian feelings, bank and electronic factory jobs, women's liberation, hippy scene in San Francisco, drugs and street life, pregnancy, bakery production, Teamsters Local 629, early 1970's welfare, her enrollment in the University of Massachusetts, women's studies, coming out in feminist/socialist scene in 1974, cab driving, District 65 Paperback Booksmith warehouse organizing drive, alcoholism and sobriety, non-union school bus drivers solidarity, butch identity, involvement with Workers World Local 8751, lesbian union culture, bus yard harrassment and a brawl with a homophobe.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref36" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Jim Monk</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Apr 28, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_b0064d5b80eea1f48a3b66548e19f285" label="master cassette [31142054612455]" type="Box">4</container>
          <container id="aspace_be2b9c48c0751c03d4aa23282c99e57b" parent="aspace_b0064d5b80eea1f48a3b66548e19f285" type="Cassette">61-62</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_90ed5b71bad460ce6850a56a2ad50bf9" label="access cd [31142054612489]" type="Box">5</container>
          <container id="aspace_a3eba5086eb56dd78b39f7092326c0df" label="digital_access_copy" type="E-records">tamwag_oh039</container>
          <container id="aspace_baed6d9297159a35b2f484f8d4e01bd8" parent="aspace_a3eba5086eb56dd78b39f7092326c0df" type="E-records">ref36_00001, ref36_00002</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_023f3bb3aeaae591343a7c8329094375">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Windsor/Ontario (Detroit). Monk was raised in Windsor in a Jehovah's Witness family. He received intense Jehovah's Witness training and struggled with his religious identity and outsiderness. His interview covers the topics of gay feelings and religion, his mother's schizophrenia, high school politics, an underground student newspaper "Thot," influence of feminist anti-war radical nun Pat Noonan, Windsor Labour Center, NDP "Waffle" factional politics, his bisexual sister, Chrysler truck assembly work, wildcat safety sitdown 1974, Johnsonite influences CLR James and Marty/Jessie Glaberman, UAW reps (Local 444), Raisa Dunayevskaya and News &amp; Letters, Local 444 rank and file membership caucus confronting layoff politics, ostracism from closeted gay co-workers, gay scene in Windsor and Detroit, CBC-TV and sister coming out, CAW pro-activity on all harassment, comaprison of Canadian gay issues, AIDS service activism, Windsor school board election 1978, negotiating same-sex spousal benefits, gay contingent in Windsor Labour Day parade, and spousal benefits for Windsor casino workers 1994-1995.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref62" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Ann Montague</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Jul 16, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_d900e4c4d57358bb21707b6ff97ed0b0" label="master cassette [31142054612471]" type="Box">6</container>
          <container id="aspace_a852c118d05b9a312540c69ceb33362b" parent="aspace_d900e4c4d57358bb21707b6ff97ed0b0" type="Cassette">107-108</container>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_8045f7ef3dfdc4c52e6ac5d913977f81" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_b92151f0aa663e7e37ffe945f6e4ef93">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Salem (Portland, OR). Montague was raised in Washington in an academic family. Her interview touches on the topics of SWP/YSA anti-war politics in college, candidate for Secretary of State SWP in Washington, Seattle Metropolitan Community Church, MCC minister, moved to Eugene, OR to start church, city referendum overturned gay ordinance, coalition work with other churches 1975, state clerical job OPEU Local 503 SEIU in Salem 1980's, memorializing Jimmy Bryan-Portland office union staff/MCC member, Oregon State University job, unity in rank and file campaign for pay equity 1983, lesbian identity on the job, gay/lesbian SEIU activists, beneift equity, developing anti-homophobia steward training with Mary Kay Henry 1990's, Oregon Citizen's Alliance right wing attack on gays (Props 9 and 13), OPEU leadership labor/gay coalition work, caseworker Oregon Health Plan, and economics of benefit equity contrast to MCC holy unions.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref40" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Cal Noyce</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Apr 30, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_ff29816a94329f8b1d5e884359cfc13a" label="master cassette [31142054612489]" type="Box">5</container>
          <container id="aspace_b7679f94b10757d2e9a6b110a1e9f3c3" parent="aspace_ff29816a94329f8b1d5e884359cfc13a" type="Cassette">66-67</container>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_6b9aadf7eb34dd75c19003c13efd624a" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_16dcf3db78c54b904b139a83a8944311">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Salt Lake City (Detroit). Noyce grew up in Salt Lake City in an ethnically/racially mixed neighborhood. His interview discusses the topics of the Kennecott Copper strikes, family and gayness, his Mormon church background, Air National Guard service, religious condemnation of homosexuality, suicide and gay Mormons, his training as a water treatment technician, his job as a phone company service rep 1972, wildcat strike 1977, lesbian union activist friends, CWA Local 7704 in Utah, AT&amp;T breakup and restructuring, gay identity on job and union, leadership in 1983 strike, gay baiting scabs, Utah AFL-CIO, AIDS work and labor/community service projects, minority caucus activism CWA conventions, gay organizing annual CWA convention, memorial to Alex Torres CWa activist Columbus, OH, reception of gay speech at San Francisco CWA convention, position as Executive Vice President Local 7704, position as Secretary-Treasurer then President of SLC Labor Council 1994-1995, and gay community awards to Utah labor leader Ed Mayne.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref48" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Bill Olwell</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Jun 9, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_fcdeb877501cf05600529a4771b338e7" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_74bd463706f72c7387206127c759053c" label="master cassette [31142054612471]" type="Box">6</container>
          <container id="aspace_1d2e91258bcbacdf4d68b4e8f224f5fe" parent="aspace_74bd463706f72c7387206127c759053c" type="Cassette">78-80</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_6bab38599a793eb3805c6e99e308bdfc">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Washington D.C. Olwell was raised Irish Catholic in Seattle in the 1930's. He served in the Korean War, studied labor relations in college in the 1950's, and was an activist and member of Retail Clerks 1105. His interview covers the topics of the growth of his union career in the 1960's, gay awareness, Seattle gay/lesbian scene, union socials lesbian date "cover," day identity in close family, King County Labor Council President, leader in Anti-Vietnam war movement, coalition SDS, gay smear campaign, radical movements, publicly coming out in 1970, RCIA leadership/constitutional politics, International Vice President 1972, non-discrimination language constitution, campaign for William Wynn's election, Public Affairs/Communications union structural changes, negotiating merger with Meatcutters to UFCW, homophobia and tolerance, gay rights organizations, alliance with Catholic Church and AFL-CIO 1983, Gay March on Washington (AFSCME and Farmworkers) 1979, lobbying gay rights convention plank Mondale Democrats, Coors family, domestic partner benefits UFCW staff, and union at Whitman-Walker clinic.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref157" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Sally Otos</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1998/1998" type="inclusive">Aug 10, 1998</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_dde43e255ff5a46eeeeac4adb39f5839" label="master cassette [31142054612455]" type="Box">4</container>
          <container id="aspace_61e6fd087f9b7135df8c4ac9e6200290" parent="aspace_dde43e255ff5a46eeeeac4adb39f5839" type="Cassette">120-121</container>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_712c2da6bd2c9b62f5640504373f2fad" label="access cd [31142062758894]" type="Box">2</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_4cc62ebc538a380be15214f3710977bd">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in New York City.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref22" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Vince Quackenbush</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Apr 7, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_80163abc0e2763915d679637c3e44238" label="master cassette [31142054612455]" type="Box">4</container>
          <container id="aspace_558f55e20125d30e5ffcb1079dce5ef3" parent="aspace_80163abc0e2763915d679637c3e44238" type="Cassette">34-35</container>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_86940e64525e26c9a7edca7e4e851dc6" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_c65c7e64c2208086ebd3b4b1ee9944e7">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in San Francisco, CA. Quackenbush grew up in a New York State Democratic Party family in Albany. After college, he took a state government job and was a rank and file member of the Civil Service Employees union. He moved to San Francisco in 1980, took a sales job at Sears and joined Local 1100 Retail Clerks. His interview covers the topics of upstate NY gay community politics, family reactions, gay community and life in department store workplace, formation of Lesbian and Gay Labor Alliance, unionization and picketing of Castro community businesses, Gay Freedom Day parades, anti-concession contract campaign 1993, union drive San Francisco AIDS Foundation SEIU Local 798, Gay/labor Prop 84 anti-La Rouche campaign 1986, gay contract language, gay community politics, SEIU hospital workers Local 250 strike support, Building Service Eployees Local 14, International Federation of Professional and Technical Engineers Local 21 and comparison with NYC gay/labor politics.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref59" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Kim Ramsey</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Jul 14, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_071dfd8d02e94127e56e755f5349c33a" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_09d0e47ff954f084bf15b71df380f15b" label="master cassette [31142054612471]" type="Box">6</container>
          <container id="aspace_78c352f831c64abcb2c0b3e7847726f8" parent="aspace_09d0e47ff954f084bf15b71df380f15b" type="Cassette">102-103</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_b3a3d6fa9096731d35c758ef4dca0f52">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Seattle. Ramsey was raised in Dearborn, Michigan to parents who were doctors with anti-racist values. Her interview covers the topics of Quaker boarding school, Alabama cajuns at summer job clothing sweatshops 1960's, Ypsilanti welding job at brother's machine tool shop, sexism at machine shops, being hired at General Electric jet engine plant IUE #1002 1984, inspiration of union activism, SWP, campaign vice president 1002, SLUw leadership seminars, Gloria Johnson at Evergreen State Women's Summer school gay/lesbian seminar 1990, confronting homphobia, conservatism, union reform, international solidarity, Hormel P-9 strike, red-baiting late 1980's, GE industrial policy and international trade, IUE internal politics, Staff Washington Public Employees Association, IUE discrimination resolution at IUE regional conference, and gay baiting as a mask for racism.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref49" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Teresa Rankin</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Jun 9, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_d6fb89aa4785070532e0b0cc5b20e881" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_9cf50d8d61b69aaaf8fb0d7ead0ccecd" label="master cassette [31142054612471]" type="Box">6</container>
          <container id="aspace_e62cc07cab88ec66a10a6d1f19a4f436" parent="aspace_9cf50d8d61b69aaaf8fb0d7ead0ccecd" type="Cassette">81-82</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_fccaee00566ed429697f33d6def2fa66">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Washington D.C. Rankin was raised in rural Virigina in a rural Southern Baptist mill town. Her interview touches on the topics of segregation and civil rights 1960's, college and radical influence, coming out in the women's movement early 1970's, DC lesbian/feminist scene, JP Stevens boycott staff Baltimore 1976-1981, separating lesbian community life from union work, ACTWU mentors and social life, SLUW older lesbian scene, pressure of union life, union/lesbian identity, AFL-CIO IUD and TWU staff, union organizers and male culture, coordinating 1983 Civil Rights March on Washington and gay question, NEA staff 1986, gay/lesbian AFL-CIO reception March on Washington 1987, gay men teachers 1990's, 1993 March and AFL-CIO and NEA receptions, and DC Lambda Labor.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref161" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Amanda Ream</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2008/2008" type="inclusive">Nov 10, 2008</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_35fbdc7b1330081b40597a9c55d59767" label="master cassette [31142054612455]" type="Box">4</container>
          <container id="aspace_6ded187db839134f193bb77ef508eb68" parent="aspace_35fbdc7b1330081b40597a9c55d59767" type="Cassette">124-125</container>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_12eb6d01382d4f6599186493fc90d371" label="access cd [31142062758894]" type="Box">2</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_f7e4b5a66c7a94ba9c7285d8201ec4cb">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in New York City.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref35" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Ron Rebant</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Apr 27, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_ab7d81f503795d75bf4d4d1305a7a535" label="access cd [31142062758886]" type="Box">1</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_d018e2109754f9db7b9f4db0144a69b7" label="master cassette [31142054612489]" type="Box">5</container>
          <container id="aspace_21409cb865bbb6a789870f2c68f16a97" parent="aspace_d018e2109754f9db7b9f4db0144a69b7" type="Cassette">60</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_f81fbe049cbc3beada8e07b66d4c9b20">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in East Pointe (Detroit). Rebant was raised in Warren, and his father was a union steward at Chrysler. Rebant was in a straight marriage for 8 years and had two kids before he came out. His interview discusses the topics of estrangment and divorce, the court ordering against kids' visit when his partner is present, his ex-wife's outing campaign to supervisor at work and to entire family, changes in technology, his desire to have his partner Ed on his health plan, meeting other Chrysler (non-union) gay workers, Ron Woods present at Ed/Ron's wedding, Chrysler redneck work culture, gossip, women co-workers who were visible lesbians. </p>
          <p>NOTE: Ron's partner Ed Preby makes occassional comments. </p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref56" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Scott Reed</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Jul 13, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_47150df9dd5e4394e2ff446dc986e85d" label="access cd [31142062758894]" type="Box">2</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_68b0c8f3b61f26a8064acc44ea52dc70" label="master cassette [31142054612471]" type="Box">6</container>
          <container id="aspace_f598f4950e40d8ffbf3137917cf212b4" parent="aspace_68b0c8f3b61f26a8064acc44ea52dc70" type="Cassette">99</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_e5111b0f9d9b1565be7bab79b377a679">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Seattle. Reed was raised in an Air Force family and was a member of the newly unionized mental health agency Bremerton UFCW #381 1988. His interview discusses the topics of bisexual identity, crisis union involvement/client repsonsibility, strike threat, controversy union history/ULP charge, gay identity in the workplace, HERE #8 staff job, rapport with gay banquet workers, coping with overt sexual harassment from older straight official, Local 8 contingent Seattle Gay Pride 1990, staff SEIU/1199 Northwest, queer caucus, organizing OutFront Labor Coalition, fighting anti-gay initiatives 608/610, union marches Gay Pride, Hands off Washington coalition, COPe convention 1993, organizer burnout quit 1199, training gig IFPTE #17 and proposing job share with lesbian friend 1994-1995.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref8" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Rosalie Regal</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Feb 14, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Manuscript box - Letter - Half" id="aspace_fbd3536eff66197778db814f88a824b4" label="transcript [31142062672103]" type="Box">3</container>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_de3a33063ec2a6801b593f9b843bad8b" label="access cd [31142062758894]" type="Box">2</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_bbc172b95b8780a8e9546b78188c71c7" label="master cassette [31142054612455]" type="Box">4</container>
          <container id="aspace_3c324acc91157109c43963024f0529fd" parent="aspace_bbc172b95b8780a8e9546b78188c71c7" type="Cassette">8-9</container>
        </did>
        <altformavail id="aspace_504bf824779da04a9713d0371a5ece1a">
          <head>Existence and Location of Copies</head>
          <p>A transcript of this interview is available at the Tamiment Library.</p>
        </altformavail>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_23e95faac333d4a9e856cdb650855ab8">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>An alternate spelling of this interviewee's last name may be "Riegel." This interview took place in Brooklyn, NY. Regal's interview covers topics such as coming out in the lesbian bar world in the late 1950's, house parties, outlaw life, alcoholism, lesbian working class jobs, butch dressing, marriage, lesbian pulp literature, Daughters of Bilitis, importance of feminist influences, sobriety in the 1970's, Women in the Trades, her entry into the telephone crafts at age 47, rank and file movements, local politics in CWA 1101, her activity in the <emph render="underline">Bell Ringer</emph>, cameraderie and pressure, sexual harrassment, racism, lesbian identity in the workplace, changing technologies, job transfers and gener discrimination grievance.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref45" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Bill Roberts</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">May 19, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_844c9bae2589e5a9e145aefb91428f33" label="master cassette [31142054612489]" type="Box">5</container>
          <container id="aspace_2e3f39c2bab1b886f49cc3ae90691086" parent="aspace_844c9bae2589e5a9e145aefb91428f33" type="Cassette">72-73</container>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_9ee66944f5647ce35f60e95e2438d6d1" label="access cd [31142062758894]" type="Box">2</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_9557283850f58e834f135641e07e42f5">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Glendale (Los Angeles). Roberts was raised in Philadelphia in a Navy family during World War II. He was trained in the Metropolitan Opera ballet and was married at age 17 with multiple theatrical union memberships. His interview covers the topics of stagework culture and queer feelings, bisexual living, street and porno world California, double life, alcoholism, show business, being a choreographer with showgirls in Las Vegas, fighting NBC/Disney on issue of dance floor safety, sponsorship by George Meany to learn labor law, AGVA rep early 1970's, leadership of lengthy widely publicized Disneyland strike, picket line actions, OPEIU Local 30 project, sobriety 1972, father/son coming out to each other, living iwth AIDS since 1987, friendship with his wife, leaving AGVA, Gwen Newton union mentor, teaching labor arbitration UCLA, confronting homophobia at union functions, March on Washington AFL-CIO reception 1993, activity in HIV/AIDS community "Fightback" classes at community centers, and newspaper column "Fightback" as bridge of union politics and HIV/AIDS community.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref41" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Faith Robinson</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Apr 30, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_721647ab630bc11ed75d24437fcec31c" label="access cd [31142062758894]" type="Box">2</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_07547f70a9e33773ea12568fbd66d9db" label="master cassette [31142054612489]" type="Box">5</container>
          <container id="aspace_0d150c516179334fecd151ff63910488" parent="aspace_07547f70a9e33773ea12568fbd66d9db" type="Cassette">68-69</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_25251e69cd6158255d35d6b99ad1422a">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Detroit. Robinson was raised in Ohio in a church missionary family. She converted to Judaism and was married with two daughters. She was a W. Michigan NOW officer and came out in the mid-1970's. She was divorced and moved to Detroit receiving a job in the Orkan exterminating business. Her interview covers the topics of the Detroit lesbian and Jewish scene, her difficult family past, acquiring blue-collar work skills, her job as a line technician at Michigan Bell, lesbian baiting and harassment while on probation, CWA Local 4100, controversy in CLUW Non-Traditional Work Committee, her promotion to splicer, coming out on the job, Detroit CLUW, president Detroit NOW, CLUW activism in mid-1980's, camparison of the two organizations and issues of coming out in CLUW.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref51" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Linda Romero</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Jun 12, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_1649a840ef34a30a6fd356dd1ed28d14" label="master cassette [31142054612471]" type="Box">6</container>
          <container id="aspace_7e85676c6b01c4dc1ff5993d2f183b47" parent="aspace_1649a840ef34a30a6fd356dd1ed28d14" type="Cassette">85-86</container>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_eae74396dadb5702c74c84f59ae0ce58" label="access cd [31142062758894]" type="Box">2</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_48f3a4511973dc835e8f1a897d0d6c3b">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Washington D.C. Although herself not a lesbian, Romero was an SEIU Education Coordinator dealing primarily with lesbian/gay issues. Her interview includes the topics of being a school bus guard then driver AFSCME, union campaign Gibralter, SEMTA driver Local 1564 ATU steward 1978-1990, sexism and racism at the workplace, contract language on "sexual predilection," occupational injury, women's leadership training U/M Labor Institute summer schools, hired SEIU 1990, bisexual first husband, friendships with gay people San Francisco Castro scene, her own bisexuality in the 1970's, social justice training anti-homophobia, DC Lambda Labor, economic/moral angle on domestic partner benefits, the future of anti-homphobia work outside Lavendar Caucus influence, and the holy scriptures.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref159" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Sue Schurman</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2001/2001" type="inclusive">Jul 18, 2001</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_c0a8d60963b3dadd419d7593a1a2858e" label="master cassette [31142054612455]" type="Box">4</container>
          <container id="aspace_70cf89f09ce13823cd174bb9df99bd2a" parent="aspace_c0a8d60963b3dadd419d7593a1a2858e" type="Cassette">122-123</container>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_727d75a839b8c6d74ba850587623faeb" label="access cd [31142062758894]" type="Box">2</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_9a23f9942fffdc173813dfdb35528e2c">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Washington D.C.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref55" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Rita Shaw</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Jul 12, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_a3e5615e0175f5ab119376592deb8c97" label="access cd [31142062758894]" type="Box">2</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_eb6ac732e541570ff684b85c8568f5ad" label="master cassette [31142054612471]" type="Box">6</container>
          <container id="aspace_1d47855678021e0797a1d3d545083a35" parent="aspace_eb6ac732e541570ff684b85c8568f5ad" type="Cassette">95-98</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_54126db8aebc6d800c3c8e47dd2be83b">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Seattle, Washington.</p>
          <p>Tape #095: Shaw was raised in the Bronx/Brooklyn to East European Orthodox Jewish immigrants. Her father was active in the Furrier's Union in the 1930's. This tape covers the topics of boarding school lesbian subculture, rebellion against religion and arranged marriage, Zionism, Communist Party youth politics, Teen Trotskyite SWP/YSA activism, interracial dates, her marriage to NMY Seaman Ed Shaw, streetfights CP/SWP, anti-red fight NMU, anti-military activism late 1940's, her move to LA, supermarket clerk RCLA, party split cochran and more to Detroit early 1950's.</p>
          <p>Tape #096: Detroit: rebuilding SWP red scare and recession, banquet waitress jobs/union, electoral campaigns, abortion network Dr. Ed Keemer jailed 1950's, previous abortions, raising kids, Cuba tour and Fair Play for Cuba, move to NYC, marriage conflict, NYC schools activism, SWP male chauvinism, separation 1960's, Seattle feminist scene NOW, abortion rights and anti-war movements. </p>
          <p>Tape #097: Rita as an unemployed single mother, NOW activism, SWP conflicts, landmark cases reproductive rights, celibacy, feminism and marriage, karate and weapons mid-1970's, Seattle CLUW, ERA coalition, sexuality and identity, relationship with partner Joan Sandler, issues with her teenage kids, and SWP industrial union campaigns.</p>
          <p>Tape #098: Railroad job BRAC (now TCIU) since 1979, non-traditional women railroad crafts, lesbian workers, union democracy, technology and job losses early 1980's, 32/40 work week campaign, Lodge President Peter Palpano then red-baited her, CLUW support red-baiting phase, SWP mass expulsions 1984, Central America coalition CLUW support, SWP opposition and CP ally 1985 and union social events.   </p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref46" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Van Sheets</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Jun 8, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_9399b6bf716f837fcffc6ba0fecd83a3" label="master cassette [31142054612471]" type="Box">6</container>
          <container id="aspace_645778e8db5db3730f6a90e4a0089c0a" parent="aspace_9399b6bf716f837fcffc6ba0fecd83a3" type="Cassette">74-75</container>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_10aaab80bced5e79842b784c83e77f41" label="access cd [31142062758894]" type="Box">2</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_e16fb648781ca1ad9fbd1ec6a1b055ab">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Washington  D.C. Sheets had a Republican upbringing in Washington D.C. This interview covers the topics of AFSCME staff 1982, gay identity and union work, feminism, culture of union headquarters/field, AFSCME gay/lesbian politics and leadership, AFL-CIO headquarters gay receptions 1987 and 1993, tasks of DC Lambda Labor, unionizing non-profit gay organizations, comparison of Whitman Walker and NYC GMHC campaigns, partner's death 1989, being HIV positive for ten years, confronting homophobia, AFSCME lesbians, "gaydar," anti-gay rights campaigns, headquarter party drag performance and AFSCME lesbian/gay advisory committee work of regional councils.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref163" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Irving Smith</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1999/1999" type="inclusive">Aug 9, 1999</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_25ace277ec6b2d37c00a359177e2f5ff" label="master cassette [31142054612455]" type="Box">4</container>
          <container id="aspace_8db29dafe5dd5ef18720eeebd0b6f478" parent="aspace_25ace277ec6b2d37c00a359177e2f5ff" type="Cassette">124-125</container>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_d032f302931efeeaaa2d58a0ebe560e6" label="access cd [31142062758894]" type="Box">2</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_4a6ac5b748ccbcb36ac9e278a33864d0">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in New York City.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref12" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Sidney Sushman</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Mar 22, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_b9cd1bc99c818fc05c5768ff0cc94034" label="access cd [31142062758894]" type="Box">2</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_7549b55febacc71cf19b0ddbacdb9e65" label="master cassette [31142054612455]" type="Box">4</container>
          <container id="aspace_efcc5f1a7f796935abf8ab1089e746fa" parent="aspace_7549b55febacc71cf19b0ddbacdb9e65" type="Cassette">17-18</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_e1af4370e2cb869a049e45bdd15752c4">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>A pseudonym for this interviewee may be "Sylvia Sidney." This interview took place in Boston, MA. Sushman was a drag and vaudeville performer known as Sylvia Sidney "The Bitch of Boston" and was greatly popular in the nightclub and gay bar scene of the 1950's and 1960's. Sushman joined the Hotel Waiters Local 34 in the early 1960's. This interview covers the topics of life in drag, after hours nightclub performances, union parties, picket duty in drag, rank and file participation, changes in union administation in the 1980's, Social Security, and the Sequins for 1981 Solidarity Day rally in Washington DC.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref32" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Sal Rosselli</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Apr 13, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_d38acb346e93ba68e897d26bef3ee298" label="access cd [31142062758894]" type="Box">2</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_28746a7d5254e04667151f87c4da706a" label="master cassette [31142054612489]" type="Box">5</container>
          <container id="aspace_2a76e97c9432b0a64af1c2081932bcdf" parent="aspace_28746a7d5254e04667151f87c4da706a" type="Cassette">55</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_60f985160c7440eeffbe49b6ddc0ab78">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Oakland, CA. Rosselli was raised in a union family in Albany, NY. He was expelled from Catholic college for anti-ROTC organizing and was involved in the Catholic Worker movement in the Lower East Side of NYC. He moved to California in the early 1970's. His interview discusses the topics of VISTA rural Indiana, community college politics during pre-med school, his job as a janitor and involvement of Local 9 Service Employees, theater janitors strike, Alice B Toklas Democratic Club, first openly gay delegate on the San Francisco Labor Council, homphobia and allies, SEIU Local 250 AIDS education, Local 9 strike and gay community theater boycott during first run of "Making Love" in the early 1980's, president "Alice," Democratic Convention, field rep Local 250 and Kaiser-Permanente strike, election and gay baiting 1987-1988, work of AIDS committee, SEIU Lavendar Caucuses, and SEIU internal politics.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref34" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Keith Truett</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Apr 27, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_cb9765e0eb72f4f63a42da938e0859b7" label="access cd [31142062758894]" type="Box">2</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_3ac77bc66841621ebe302effff27adb3" label="master cassette [31142054612489]" type="Box">5</container>
          <container id="aspace_46f8e8c0cbf27e55c5b4860225e6f063" parent="aspace_3ac77bc66841621ebe302effff27adb3" type="Cassette">58-59</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_87856a937aaccd8855b2f5580201b16c">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Ypsilanti (Detroit). Truett was raised in Dearborn in a UAW Local 600 family. He worked in the same auto parts shop as both of his parents and brother all of whom were accepting of his gayness. His interview covers the topics of family life and support of union struggles, gay men in plant and gay community, his mother's work with HIV positive workers, gay clique and gossip, other workers' awareness, visible butch lesbian co-workers, gay families and divorces in his family, gays in his neighborhood, his desire to follow his mother as Local 600 benefit rep, coming out to co-workers, AIDS, harassment of Ron Woods and the plant as community.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref181" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Martha Voland</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2009/2009" type="inclusive">Jul 16,2009</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Manuscript box - Letter - Half" id="aspace_da3f76f897d9da8f4f2f0376f6215b7b" label="transcript [31142062672103]" type="Box">3</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref53" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Kurt Vorndran</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Jun 13, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_c3a2bf12065c5040f27e192e7c98bb3c" label="access cd [31142062758894]" type="Box">2</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_532685402d4a39b50fcc64205e4364ca" label="master cassette [31142054612471]" type="Box">6</container>
          <container id="aspace_fc3b64430b9ccaba11923ab9fd898de5" parent="aspace_532685402d4a39b50fcc64205e4364ca" type="Cassette">89-90</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_643c774e84defd5901241580c509ca5c">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Washington D.C. Vorndran was raised in rural Wisconsin to a storekeeper/farmer family. His interview covers the topics of progressivism, coming out late 1970's, national gay rights March 1979, political activism, Common Cause, DC amendment organizing, gay/lesbian Democratic club early 1980's, raising gay consciousness among allies, social issues and cultural conservatism, AFL-CIO Full Employment campaign, National council Senior Citizens late 1980's, comparison of national gay rights AFL-CIO receptions 1987 and 1993, DC Lambda Labor, assistant director of Legislation and Political Action CLUW, gay rights in IUE, union gay role models were Bill Olwell and Tom Kahn.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref54" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Bailey T. Walker Jr. </unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Jun 14, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_244b96019c94db3af4c462ed26f14720" label="access cd [31142062758894]" type="Box">2</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_eff2f0902df218da5f654208dd4f3ffe" label="master cassette [31142054612471]" type="Box">6</container>
          <container id="aspace_c8794b73a274c61fc5701def8d5eb3cc" parent="aspace_eff2f0902df218da5f654208dd4f3ffe" type="Cassette">91-92</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_906847084d59eee639fdb3b7c2c419e2">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Washington D.C. Walker was raised in the suburbs of Richmond, VA in a military family. His interview discusses the topics of Catholic progressivism, Dominican vows, being ordained a priest at St. Vincent in NYC, gay/religious moral conflicts, gay friends on AFSCME organizing staff Florida, leaving the Dominicans, transfer to DC AFSCME headquarters Education Department, homophobia and gay identity in regions and headquarters, AFSCME gay/lesbian activists Vic Basile (DC), Tom Sadnicki and Barry Friedman (Chicago), Atlantic City convention resolution on gay rights spoken for by Secretary Treasurer Wm. Lucy 1982, HQ staff and diversity training, racial tensions, gay/union work of Tom and Barry Council 31, church/union hierarchies and ethics, and domestic strains and supports.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref26" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Howard Wallace</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Apr 8, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_3156c094336528011ddc63656c4eca11" label="access cd [31142062758894]" type="Box">2</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_c2192e1f0f2e8afc53c1108478bff758" label="master cassette [31142054612489]" type="Box">5</container>
          <container id="aspace_83604e3c941c93a4a54d5423df70dd4e" parent="aspace_c2192e1f0f2e8afc53c1108478bff758" type="Cassette">40-43</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_438bf5670adbf4ccf1e33618c38e959d">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in San Francisco, CA. </p>
          <p>Tape #040: Wallace was raised in Worcester, Ma and Denver, CO. Topics include memories of youth during World War II, sickliness, gay feelings, liberal ideas and friends, McCarthyism, "silent generation." University of Denver NAACP electoral work, Students for Democratic Action, United World Federalists, clash with parents, closet existence, suicidal thoughts, and his Socialist Workers Party contacts of the late 1950's. </p>
          <p>Tape #041: Denver SDA screening of "Salt of the Earth," joined SWP, contact with Communist Party, civil rights support, Fair Play for Cuba, closet danger in gay life, homophobic remark Farrell Dobbs, closet affair SWP comrade, cruising and bars, gay sublimination and politics early 1960's, thoughts on Bayard Rustin and James Baldwin, Committee Against Police Brutality, organizing successes and New Left anti-war movement, GI work, moves to San Francisco, Teamster job Local 856, anti-war electoral politics demonstrations late 1960's, SWP anti-war labor organizing and gay issues early 1970's. </p>
          <p>Tape #042: San Francisco gay/hippy scene, anti-war organizing, coming out in movement and influence of lesbian question in NOW 1971, bar world, gay liberation, drifting away from SWP, Maoists in Revolutionary Gay Men's Union, job at peanut factory early 1970's, start of Bay Area Gay Liberation, popularity of BAGL, Harvey Milk's populism, Board of Education campaign 1975, Coors boycott, Teamster Local 888. Allan Baird's work with gay community, brewery workers, national boycott organizer and AFL-CIO work 1980's. </p>
          <p>Tape #043: Coors campaign and lawsuit, gay community work and mass protests in BAGL, leftist splits, placement by Baird as first openly gay beer truck driver Teamsters Local 888, gay identity and Teamsters, AFL-CIO convention mid-1970's, clashes with Milk over Farmworkers grape boycott support, BAGL and building gay/labor consensus for city worker support mid-1970's, DC gay march and AFL-CIO headquarter reception 1987, recognition in SF labor movement, Local 250 Service Employees and work with Sal Rosselli of Theater Janitors Service Employees Local 9, their strike and gay community theater boycott first run of "Making Love."</p>
          <p>NOTE: Howard Wallace's work is also mentioned in interviews with Gary Dotterman, Tom Ammiano, Vince Quackenbush, Leslie Manning, Nancy Wohlforth, Walter Johnson, Allan Baird, Hank Wilson, and Sal Rosselli. </p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref18" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Karen Wheeler </unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Mar 26, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_19b5a6407f32ac3de5ea7d183bf2b6eb" label="access cd [31142062758894]" type="Box">2</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_f77d91c8fc50e37a8360c7f834f20e24" label="master cassette [31142054612455]" type="Box">4</container>
          <container id="aspace_c90a814c6d7ade00f1fa7f51aaf739fe" parent="aspace_f77d91c8fc50e37a8360c7f834f20e24" type="Cassette">29</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_467fa5b9109c5859af6636a3f2cf26c8">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Boston, MA. Wheeler grew up in Connecticut, spent her teenage years in South Carolina as a "tomboy/nerd" and came out in Boston in 1973. Her interview covers the topics of lesbian bars/sports scene, her 1976 welder apprentice at Quincy Shipyard Local 5 Shipbuilders, left organizations, women union members' democracy issues, non-traditional work, lesbian workplace invisibility after-work culture, age, ethnic, racial and gender issues, asbestos, Boston City Hospital Service Employees Local 285, integration of lesbian and union life, gay/lesbian hospital workers, GALLAN and Fenway Clinic benefit, harassment, workplace romances and domestic partner benefits.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref31" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Hank Wilson</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Apr 12, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_4fba7846c896bcdbe017ebca0b413896" label="access cd [31142062758894]" type="Box">2</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_f074d77c52379e4045779ae33370c1fa" label="master cassette [31142054612489]" type="Box">5</container>
          <container id="aspace_d02f80191c912eafadbc83c8feb941c3" parent="aspace_f074d77c52379e4045779ae33370c1fa" type="Cassette">53-54</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_02f901cebec39a22d6a308e63deb21f8">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in San Francisco, CA. Wilson was raised in Sacramento and was educated at UCLA and University of Wisconsin. His interview covers the topics of VISTA, anti-war activism, FBI harassment, his move to San Francisco in the early 1970's, Bay Area Gay Liberation, street organizing Castro, politics and Left, Board of Education anti-discrimination policy work with Tom Ammiano, parent support of gay teachers, lobbying, teachers coming out, Gay Teachers Coalition work with black community, Gay Democratic Club, Florida Save our Children, Briggs inititative, Larry Burner openly gay teacher in Healdsburg late 1970's, Gay Freedom Day visibility, youth suicide prevention, his 17 years of homeless work at the Ambassador Hotel and development of AIDS outreach.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref28" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Nancy Wohlforth</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Apr 11, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_abb90715914b4c459fff9d8d6806e23c" label="access cd [31142062758894]" type="Box">2</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_294e88a2e371902a4dd41540eba8b5c9" label="master cassette [31142054612489]" type="Box">5</container>
          <container id="aspace_0570577b5302f52fca5ad997a80cf6fa" parent="aspace_294e88a2e371902a4dd41540eba8b5c9" type="Cassette">48-49</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_c4a94455ecff1f68b7eacc4346b0aca4">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in San Francisco, CA. Wohlforth was raised in Milwaukee in a union family affiliated with AFSCME. Her interview covers the topics of socialist values, student/worker alliance 1968, feminism, socialist group (Workers League), Socialist Workers Party, VISTA, NYC anti-war work, SWP, Coors, gay community politics, gay/union coalition work, domestic partner benefits, VISTA welfare rights sit-ins, Textile Workers JP Stevens campaign, SWP Steelworkers insurgency and Lordstown Autoworkers, Office and Professional Local 3 union politics, Gay Freedom Day, gay indentity in OPEIU, CLUW and NOW in the early 1980's, clerical jobs, her election to Vice President of Local 3 as open lesbian, baiting, gay themes in Local 3 organizing campaigns, gay/lesbian presence in OPEIU, and support from union feminists.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref155" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Nancy Wohlforth</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2006/2006" type="inclusive">Jun 18, 2006</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_74621ec441226802980c1d75a9adb27c" label="master cassette [31142054612455]" type="Box">4</container>
          <container id="aspace_01fa7935702a506e15ee6f279df22798" parent="aspace_74621ec441226802980c1d75a9adb27c" type="Cassette">118-119</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_19031ab7ff6f114cc283f691ac41e159">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Maryland.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref33" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Ron Woods</unittitle>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">Apr 27, 1995</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Card Box - 6.5 - long" id="aspace_fbdbfdaa88ef8b1612a8913658507841" label="access cd [31142062758894]" type="Box">2</container>
          <container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 9.5" id="aspace_1c810ac426d2f42b49ac17a8cdd1cf79" label="master cassette [31142054612489]" type="Box">5</container>
          <container id="aspace_759937b5ac524fe85b06f3dec0a1a617" parent="aspace_1c810ac426d2f42b49ac17a8cdd1cf79" type="Cassette">56-57</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_a4bcf906270be56319c1c5fce2667e23">
          <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
          <p>This interview took place in Huntington Woods (Detroit). Woods was raised in a Detroit suburb in a construction union family. He was a member of Local 412 UAW. His interview covers the topics of coming out to his family, working overtime at Chrysler, details of mobilizing grass roots coalition and demonstrations against Cracker Barrel in autumn of 1991, zaps and corporate campaign tactics, press coverage leading to public exposure, his 4 year apprenticeship as an auto eletrician from 1986-1990, shop culture, homphobic factory scene, Cracker Barrel news stories and reactions, ostracism, harassment, death threats, his transfer to a new worksite in August, UAW solidarity civil rights story 1993, standing up to his manager, co-worker respect, campaigning for UAW 1995 Constitutional Convention delegate and being baited by his opponent.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
